

BUDDIKA DISSANAYAKE

MEDICAL DOCTOR & ENTREPRENEUR

buddika.dm@yahoo.com

+94 766 265 053

Trilingual medical graduate with 15 years of entrepreneurial experience in business leadership in Russia and Sri Lanka. Experienced in all aspects of business management, operation, formation, and finance. Founded a thriving online apparel business with a four year turnover of 320,000 USD. Established and fully managed four different hospitality businesses in Sri Lanka. A relentless optimist who believes there is no failure, only feedback.

RUSSIAN

ENGLISH

SINHALESE

EDUCATION

St. Petersburg I. I. Mechnikov state medical academy 09/2002 to 06/2008 Doctor of Medicine (MD)

FOR FUN

Traveling, Cooking, Fitness and Yoga, Woodworks, History, Languages, Cars

SKILLS

Leadership | Empowering motivator | Time and task management Creative and resourceful | Can-do attitude | Diligent Team management and coaching | Multitasking | Open-minded EQ and patience

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

INTERNATIONAL RUSSIAN TEACHER November 2019 - Present

- Conducting biweekly offline classes for two groups of 15 students each and six weekly personalized one-on-one Zoom lessons.
- Teaching history and descent of Russian and Slavic language groups.
- Systematizing, elaborating and editing the sequence of an easy flow schedule of 24 (three-hour) lessons.
- Achieving students' speaking and comprehension skills from A0 to A2 in three months.
- Developing eight multimedia presentations using videos and slideshows to orchestrate interactive activities.
- Implementing graded tests and homework for progress tracking.
- Incorporating slow-paced reading, Russian podcasts and Russian dubbed English movie sessions.

RUSSIAN TOURIST GUIDE & PROPERTY REALTOR (Sri Lanka) August 2015 - Present

- Planning custom-made excursions for various size groups.
- Marketing and developing a group on VK.com with 25K followers.
- Publishing engaging tourism content on VK.com, Moyaplaneta.ru.
- Reviewing, listing and leasing holiday properties from 15 landlords.
- Organized a wedding for a Russian TV channel "Friday".
- Continuously achieving a 100% client satisfaction as well as a high rate of returned clients.

BUSINESS PARTNER AT SURFCAMPFORYOU.RU (Sri Lanka) August 2018 - Present

• Local representative for all operations: the surf-spot and the camp facility that accommodates 28 students at a time.

FOUNDER, SURF'S UP AHANGAMA (Sri Lanka) September 2018 - April 2019

- Established and ran a guesthouse & restaurant with a total operating turnover of \$75,000 within six months.
- Recruited, trained and supervised five members of staff.
- Reached 100% of guesthouse booking capacity within a month of operation.
- Achieved 4.8/5 Airbnb Superhost status; 9.5/10 Booking.com; 5/5 TripAdvisor; 4.6/5 Google.
- Analyzed and monitored budgets, funds and expenses.

FOUNDER, DACHA RESTAURANT, BAR & CINEMA (Sri Lanka) August 2016 - May 2017

- Opened the very first Russian restaurant and the only western style cocktail bar in Unawatuna.
- Completely renovated derelict premises to an upscale and contemporary establishment containing outdoor cinema and hookah lounge.
- Recruited 16 professional restaurant, bar and PR staff from Russia.
- Arranged accommodation for foreign employees as well as helping them to adapt to a new country.
- Developed and designed a fascinating food and drinks menu.

CO-OWNER, SURF LANKA ME SURFING SCHOOL (Sri Lanka) September 2015 - April 2017

- Founded a surfing school for beginners aimed at the Russian market.
- Managed two guesthouses designated for the students.
- Organized the full program for the guests: surfing, dinners, events and recreational activities.
- Hired two Russian surfing instructors.

E-COMMERCE SHOP OWNER (Russia)

June 2008 - March 2014

- Sold over 1,000 pieces of merchandise each year with annual revenue of over \$80,000.
- Created, developed and traded through a VK.com group with 35K followers and customers.
- Analyzed Yandex.ru search engine statistics and data to forecast demand for popular clothing brands which led to the launch of three individual shopping websites.
- Carried out meticulous SEO and marketing activity to reach the top ten positions within Yandex.ru.
- Expanded doorstep deliveries all over Russia with courier services that outperformed previous VK.com group sales by 70%.
- Opened a warehouse and two central offices.
- Hired and fully trained three sales managers.
- Optimized and monitored orders from China through international and local logistics.
- Successfully sold the business in 2014 for \$40,000.

PARAMEDIC, YELIZAVETINSKAYA BOL'NITSA HOSPITAL (Russia)

November 2008 - June 2010

CAR BUYER AND RESELLER (Russia)

October 2004 - August 2008

PART-TIME WAITER AND SOMMELIER AT RUSSKIJ CLUB RESTAURANT (Russia)

June 2004 - December 2006